<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Sorashi</title><link>https://sorashi.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Sorashi</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://sorashi.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The .NET Drama of PR 22217</title><link>https://sorashi.github.io/net-drama/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sorashi.github.io/net-drama/</guid><description>On October 20th, the PR #22217 was created (and later merged) in the dotnet/sdk repository. This change, named Remove Hot Reload support from dotnet watch, removed this awaited feature from the dotnet CLI and left it available only in Visual Studio 2022. Note that this change was done a few days before .NET 6 release (releasing on 2021-11-08), removing it from this version. The PR removed around 2,500 lines of code from the .</description></item><item><title>Number of zeros at the end of a factorial in logarithmic time</title><link>https://sorashi.github.io/number-of-zeros-at-the-end-of-factorial-in-logarithmic-time/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sorashi.github.io/number-of-zeros-at-the-end-of-factorial-in-logarithmic-time/</guid><description>You might think that knowing the number of zeros that suffix the value of $n!$ is useless. And you might be right. At least I haven&amp;rsquo;t thought of any use.
Even though, I want to leave this here, because I found this out while solving something else.
So the problem is:
Given $n$, return the maximum number of zeros, that suffix $n!$. For example for $n=5$, $n! = 15511210043330985984000000$, so the answer would be $6$.</description></item><item><title>Asus E200HA Arch Linux Installation Guide</title><link>https://sorashi.github.io/asus-e200ha-arch/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sorashi.github.io/asus-e200ha-arch/</guid><description>Foreword Oh, the Asus E200HA! A small Intel Cherry Trail netbook with 32GB of internal memory and 2 gigs of RAM. I bought one for its compact size and small weight. Boy, was it a mistake. It comes with Windows 10 pre-installed and Windows 10 sure likes huge updates and general littering of your drive. The device is literally unusable after a small while. That is not a huge deal, you can just install Linux, right?</description></item><item><title>How to fix Facebook archive JSON encoding</title><link>https://sorashi.github.io/fix-facebook-json-archive-encoding/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sorashi.github.io/fix-facebook-json-archive-encoding/</guid><description>Facebook has a great feature which allows you to download an archive of your data. This includes content of messages from Messenger, posts, photos and videos, comments etc.
This allows you to display interesting statistics if you can work with JSON in a programming language. For example, whom did you message the most in the last 30 days? Who of your friends writes the longest messages? Imagination is your only limit.</description></item><item><title>(CZ) Lineární diofantické rovnice</title><link>https://sorashi.github.io/linear-diophantine-equations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sorashi.github.io/linear-diophantine-equations/</guid><description>Diofantické rovnice jsou podurčené polynomiální rovnice, u kterých se hledá řešení v množině $\mathbb{Z}$.
Lineární diofantická rovnice je rovnice ve tvaru součtu dvou monomů prvního řádu:
$$ax+by=c\,.$$
Takovým rovnostem se také říká Bézoutovy. Lze je vyřešit pomocí rozšířeného Euklidova algoritmu.
K čemu se ale řešení takových rovnic hodí? Pojďme se podívat na jednu úlohu, která se objevila v matematickém testu pro čtvrtou třídu základní školy.
Mimoni založili orchestr. Umí hrát jen na basu nebo kytaru.</description></item><item><title>A comprehensive list of Rikai extensions</title><link>https://sorashi.github.io/comprehensive-list-of-rikai-extensions/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://sorashi.github.io/comprehensive-list-of-rikai-extensions/</guid><description>There are so many rikai extensions that I got lost when I was trying to find my choice. I want this to be the go-to article for people who seek not only the full list of rikai extensions, but also the truth behind their origin.
We&amp;rsquo;ll begin with what you&amp;rsquo;re all here for:
Name Browser Repository Site nazeka Firefox, works on Android GitHub None 10ten Japanese Reader (formerly Rikaichamp) Firefox, Chrome, Safari, iOS, macOS GitHub Twitter rikaichan Chrome &amp;amp; Firefox GitHub None rikaikun Chrome GitHub None RikaiRebuilt Chrome &amp;amp; Firefox GitHub None Rikaisama Firefox (XPI, not published on Firefox addon site) None Yes rikaiXUL N/A N/A mozdev Yomichan Chrome &amp;amp; Firefox GitHub Yes Now some information about some of them:</description></item></channel></rss>